When the first wisp of wind brushed across the land
Rüzgarın ilk esintisi vurduğunda tüm diyara
Birds that yearned for the sky had wings
gökyüzüne özlem duyan kuşların kanatları vardı.
But no way to fly
Vardı ama uçmak ne mümkün?
They asked the Anemo God:
Sordular Rüzgar Tanrısı'na:
"How can we reach the heavens?"
"Nasıl uçabiliriz gökyüzüne?"
To which the Anemo God replied:
Cevap verdi Rüzgar Tanrısı:
"You have yet to find that which is most important"
"Asıl mühim olan meseleyi idrak etmeniz lazım."
As the God spoke, the wind thrust the seeds of a dandelion
Tanrı sözünü bitirmeden vurdu bir rüzgar karahindiba tohumlarına
High into the sky
ve uçurdu gökyüzünün derinliklerine.
The birds thrust out their wings
Kuşlar çırptı kanatlarını.
But the breeze was all too mild
Yine de sadece bir esinti çıktı.
Leaving them to stumble across the earth
Dünyanın dört bir yanına saçıldılar.
So they went to the gorge
Sonra da geçide vardılar.
Where the wind showed off its wild and incomparable strength
Rüzgar hiç olmadığı kadar şiddetlenmeye başladı.
They threw themselves off the cliff
Uçurumdan aşağı atladılar.
And flapped their wings amongst the howling winds
Çırptılar kanatlarını güçlü rüzgara karşı.
Until they were able to fly freely in the sky
Sonunda özgürce uçabiliyorlardı gökyüzünde.
To the Anemo God they went, to gleefully say:
Rüzgar Tanrısı'na gittiler hemen ve mutlu bir şekilde dediler ki:
"We understand now! All we needed was a stronger wind to fly"
"Artık anladık! Uçmak için ihtiyacımız olan tek şey kuvvetli bir rüzgarmış."
In reply the Anemo God said:
Rüzgar Tanrısı cevap verdi:
"What you lacked was not wind, but courage"
"Eksikliğini çektiğiniz rüzgar değil cesaretti."
"It is courage that has allowed you to become the first flying birds of this world"
"Bu dünyanın ilk uçan kuşları olmanızı sağlayan cesaret."